{
  "questions": [
    {
      "q_id": 1,
      "answer": "B",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "Two forces affect the vertical fall of a skydiver. What is the name of the force acting towards the centre of the earth?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "Buoyancy."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "Gravity."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "Law of Inertia."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "Resistance."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": 2,
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What is the focus?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "The point where most of the weight is located in the body."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "The point where I feel the most body energy."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "The intersection of all 3 body axes and therefore the center of mass."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "The point of most concentration."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": 3,
      "answer": "A",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What is the effect of the airflow due to gravitational acceleration?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "On the body surface presented."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "On focus."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "To gravity directly."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "On the distribution of weight in the body."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": 4,
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "not changed."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "twice as big."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "smaller."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "bigger."
        }
      ],
      "question": "How does the resistance depend on the value of the air density? When the air density becomes lower, the resistance..."
    },
    {
      "q_id": 5,
      "answer": "D",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "Which statement is correct?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "Gravity acts at the center of gravity."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "The air force acts on the body surface.   "
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "The center of the total air force is called the point of force application."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "All answers are correct."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": 6,
      "answer": "D",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "The incoming air transfers a force to the presented surface. Which statement is correct?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "If the point of application of force is higher than the centre of gravity, then the state of equilibrium is stable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "If the point of application of the force is below the centre of gravity, the state of equilibrium is unstable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "If the point of application of the force is at the same height as the centre of gravity, then the state of equilibrium is indifferent."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "All answers are correct."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": 7,
      "answer": "B",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What do you call the state of equilibrium during free fall in boxing position?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "indifferent."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "stable"
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "unstable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "unevenly."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "8",
      "answer": "A",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What do you call the state of equilibrium during free fall in the X position?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "stable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "unstable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "unstable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "unevenly."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "9",
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What do you call the state of equilibrium during free fall in the floater position?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "stable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "indifferent."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "unstable."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "unevenly."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "10",
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "When is a flight condition called unstable or unstable?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "When you're no longer lying on your stomach."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "In the head-down position."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "If the attitude is not controlled."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "In skysurfing and freestyle."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "11",
      "answer": "D",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "Which statement is correct? At a higher altitude...",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "air density and free fall speed are lower."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "the air density and free-fall velocity are greater."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "the air density is greater and the free fall speed is lower."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "the air density is lower and the free fall speed is higher."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "12",
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "When does a skydiver stop accelerating in freefall? When...",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "the resistance becomes greater than gravity."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "the resistance and the buoyancy are equal."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "the air force and the weight force are equal."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "the buoyancy offsets the force of gravity."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "13",
      "answer": "B",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "In near-earth air layers, the slowest free-fall speed is in the floater position, for example...",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "70km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "170km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "270km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "Three hundred and fifty miles per hour."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "14",
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "In near-Earth air layers, the average free-fall velocity in the add-down position is about...",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "70km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "180km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "250km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "400km/h."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "15",
      "answer": "C",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "In near-earth air layers, the average free-fall velocity in the boxing position is about...",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "100km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "150km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "180km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "270km/h."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "16",
      "answer": "A",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "In near-earth air layers, the average vertical fall velocity in the track is...",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "about 150km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "about 200km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "up to 290km/h."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "over 350km/h."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "17",
      "answer": "B",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What does the free fall speed depend on?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "Mass of the harness and the rate of descent."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "Mass, size and freefall attitude of the skydiver."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "Training of the parachutist."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "Shape of the parachute canopy."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "18",
      "answer": "D",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "What influences the free fall speed? ",
      "questionOptions": [
        {
          "option": 1,
          "text": "Weight and size of the jumper."
        },
        {
          "option": 2,
          "text": "Incoming flow, altimeter."
        },
        {
          "option": 3,
          "text": "Clothing, lead vest. "
        },
        {
          "option": 4,
          "text": "Airtight, free-fall position."
        }
      ],
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "Only answer 3 is correct."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "Only answer 4 is correct."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "Answers 1 and 3 are correct"
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "Answers 1, 3 and 4 are correct."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "19",
      "answer": "B",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "Which of the above body shapes has the greatest resistance with the same amount of frontal area?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "Streamline body."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "Hollow hemisphere (hollow side)."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "Vertical flow circular plate."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "Bullet."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "20",
      "answer": "D",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "Which statement is correct?",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "A body in an unstable state of equilibrium can fall in a controlled manner."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "A body in a stable state of equilibrium can fall uncontrollably."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "A body in an indifferent state of equilibrium can fall in a controlled manner."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "All answers are correct."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "q_id": "21",
      "answer": "B",
      "category": "Freefall",
      "question": "Controlling freefall is one of the goals of any parachute jump. To do this, the following should be considered:",
      "choices": [
        {
          "choice": "A",
          "value": "Physical preparation is not necessary, as skydiving is purely a head thing."
        },
        {
          "choice": "B",
          "value": "I should be physically healthy, fit and mobile, be familiar with the required postures and prepare my musculoskeletal system for the targeted tasks."
        },
        {
          "choice": "C",
          "value": "The most physically challenging part of skydiving is packing the parachute."
        },
        {
          "choice": "D",
          "value": "All answers are correct."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}